all right everybody we are back
it is jack murphy this is jack murphy
live
and we are live today at one o'clock
with darren beatty dr
darren j beatty but first a little bit
about me my name is jack murphy you can
find me on twitter at jack murphy live
at the website jackmurphylive.com the
book i wrote is called democrat 2
deplorable make sure you go out and get
that the single best explanation of what
happened in 2016
will also tell you what's going to
happen in 2020
and if you're even more interested in
what we're doing there is my all men's
organization called the liminal order
come down and check us out at
liminalhyphenorder.com but enough about
me
let's get to the guest today his name is
darren j
beatty doctor darren jb how you doing
buddy good to see you
doing great thanks thanks for having me
here yeah it's my pleasure great to have
you
um jaren uh is a well he's a political
specialist
a philosopher a mathematician he worked
in the trump white house among
other things and he's currently now
writing and involved with revolver.news
which is the latest greatest replacement
to the drudge report
as uh as told to us by the president the
other day he commented that's great
everybody go down there check it out
revolver.news stepping in to fill
the shoes of the old drudge report as
it's fallen off the map
so darren as is usual on jack murphy
live i like to give
the listeners a little bit of context
and a little bit of background on you
and we're going to talk about you and
then we're going to get to
the color revolution because i know
that's what's something that's something
everybody wants to talk about
uh you were on tucker carlson the other
night and
uh after four minutes of absolutely
riveting
uh dialogue tucker was just like totally
captivated watching you uh you got cut
off
unfortunately and you left the nation
hanging and uh everybody wanted to hear
more and so
luckily for us we had this scheduled and
i am looking forward to
picking that up as soon as uh you know
and and getting really deep into it
because we've got plenty of time here
and we can sprawl out and we can go into
all the details but first i just want to
give people a little bit of background
can you just tell us
you know where did you come from what
were you doing tell us how you got
to the trump administration and just
give a little bit of background and
we'll move through this because i know
everybody's ready to get to the good
stuff but i like
having this context so that we can get
to know you a little bit as well as the
material
great sure yeah um so i guess just
briefly about my own um biography
i grew up overseas in a little little
island in
in micronesia and before getting
involved
um very heavily and actively in politics
i was
an academic and got my academic start
as a mathematics major at the university
of chicago
many mathematicians in my family for
much of my life i thought he was going
to be a mathematician it was
still is in many ways a big part of my
life and kind of shapes the way that i
think about things
and i went on from um university of
chicago mathematics
actually for two years um in washington
and uh for those two years i worked for
a uh very um uh
intelligent and influential jurist who
is unfortunately now deceased called
judge robert bork and he was nominated
to the supreme court by reagan
and was subject to vicious media
attacks before those were just kind of
standard practice and um
was not able to make it to the supreme
court but he did get a
uh a word named after his name which is
in the dictionary called bork
which is what you know refers to these
kinds of
vicious media attacks specifically in
the context of a supreme court
nomination
right so so that was a very interesting
experience in educational for two years
and i went from there
to uh duke university to
pursue a phd in political theory
political philosophy
um i found uh german philosophers
particularly interesting
and ended up writing a dissertation of
which i am very proud
i think it's the greatest thing that
i've ever done
um it was really a spark of
of um kind of
the the creative muse uh touched me
for a period of several months and i was
able to produce something that still
impresses me and i wonder how the hell i
was able to do it because i
i could never reproduce something like
that and
um it's accessible it's on my twitter
handle if you go to at darren j
beatty i have it as a link that's
accessible for
for download you can read the abstract
sounds like a real page turner the title
is
martin heidegger's mathematical
dialectic uncovering the structure of
modernity
and don't be deterred by the title it's
not something
pedantic it's something that like what
mathematicians do mathematicians
study the structure of things and
i explore the um
go ahead of of mathematics
um developed by german philosopher
martin heidegger
and i use that robust conception that he
develops that hearkens back to the
original greek term
in order to give an original and i think
very powerful
explanation as to what the structure of
modernity
actually is and by modernity i don't
just mean
you know recent stuff that's happened in
the past couple months by modernity i
mean
that period of western history and
consciousness and understanding
inaugurated by uh the key figures
uh such as descartes galileo and newton
and
um so i can maybe get into that a little
bit more but that was
uh just a very uh important kind of
chapter in my life where i was
reading uh philosophy reading
mathematics and then
this kind of spark of creation
um uh emerged in my mind and i was able
to produce this
and i wrote much of it while i was in
germany um
which was a fun experience too well
could you could you give us just like
what what is the main takeaway from and
i know it's impossible to summarize the
dissertation in a couple of minutes but
it's important because i believe at the
time you know you're studying you're
getting your phd you're working on all
this you're
you're heavily influenced by what you're
working on and that actually turned into
sort of where you are now right there's
a there's a few direct steps that have
led
from that work to where you are and and
i'm very interested just to hear
you know you said you were inspired and
it was a great you know the thing you're
most proud of what
what is it what if if somebody read it
what what do you hope that they take
away
from it uh you know that you're so proud
of
well i think it gives a very
um deep and original account
of the structure modernity in a way that
illuminates the circumstances that we're
in today
at the broadest level how various
developments in kind of
science and mathematics and technology
and the preconditions of those
developments and how
those preconditions themselves shape
society in all kinds of
different ways to really understand
fundamentally the moment we're in now
with technology and its meaning and so
forth
you really have to go to the root of
what happened in modernity
and to be able to give a really powerful
account
for that and to give that account
through the lens
of a particular conception of what
mathematics is
now people might hear that and think oh
you know he's just like is he trying to
you know reduce the world to some kind
of math formula no
in fact this robust conception of
mathematics seduced by heidegger
is a precondition for the understanding
of mathematics in terms of number
so um so it's it's really
uh uh it's it's it's very kind of
foundational in that respect
and of course different people would get
different things out of it depending on
um you know what their background is i
mean i think
there is such a thing as sort of false
credentialism
and hiding ideas within jargon and
that's
largely obfuscatory and usually you can
explain things in much more simpler term
in much simpler
terms than usually presented by you know
academic types
but at the same time um for stuff like
this there is
something to be said for a kind of a
background
knowledge of the history of philosophy
which and the more that one has that and
the more that once kind of thought
through those questions i think
the more one gets out of it but um i
think
particularly with heidegger who's
generally
you know other than the kind of
political
controversy uh surrounding him which
people
belabor at infinitum he's also
associated with a kind of
continental european school of
philosophy
that uh is kind of criticized as being
more obscure and that
um it might be responsible for
certain academics today who hide their
own kind of mediocrity and lack of
originality
in um in jargon
and that's true 99 percent of the time
in fact many of the people who study
heidegger
are trash and have weak minds but i
think
in in this particular case heidegger
himself
truly is a deeply profound thinker i
think he's the greatest thinker of the
20th century
there's so much to be learned from him
and what the sad thing is
is that his language is a little bit um
weird and different and so people who
when they see that type of language in
you know
normally it's in the context of
something that's
trash and obscurantist it takes
a big commitment to actually give them a
chance to figure out wow
this is maybe with a one in a million
case where this new and
kind of bizarre language is actually
necessary because it's bringing to the
fore
an entirely new concept and
do you think that you could summarize
for us what the concept was i mean
my listeners to the podcast we have
talked to michael
uh michael millerman we have gone in
depth on
uh heidegger strauss dugan etc and so
there's
there's some context for our listeners
here and i you know
after talking to millerman i realized i
needed to learn a little bit more about
heidegger
myself and uh so if there's a there's
just a way you could maybe summarize
that for us and then uh you know talk
about what happened
to you after that and where did this
work lead you
right well i mean it depends in this
case what the concept is because
heidegger has developed a number of
of different concepts and terminologies
um if uh you mean the concept of math
that i you know yeah the council math
what was it that struck you the
most that that has led you to this
conclusion that one in a million let's
say
well his pre his conception of math
um is really developed in a series of
lectures about
uh immanuel kant whose first
critique was very much a kind of work of
philosophy of mathematics or really
the preconditions of thinking about the
world in such a way that
um are you know kind of mathematical
um and uh so within that context you
know heidegger kind of
uses kant but kind of more as a pretext
to riff on his own
ideas and his own ideas math really
hearken back to the greek conception
of you know mathemata
and you know interested listeners can
read say
platonic dialogue on the meno which
actually explores this
this term in this particular concept or
uh concept of memory and recollection
has the same root as tamatha mata
because according to the greeks or at
least the platonic representation of
greek thought which is not of course
monolithic but the platonic
representation of it
is that learning is actually a process
of recollection
this is what's explored in the meno and
mathematics in the sense that we
understand
in the context of geometrical problem is
used to illustrate this point that
learning is recollection and that
because
mathematics lends itself to a certain
type of clarity and certainty
it's the best means to represent the
general
truth that learning is recollection and
they go into a really interesting
kind of metaphysics as it were of saying
that we're actually
recollecting things that we've learned
in past lives so there's
there's a whole interesting kind of
narrative to it as well that is not
necessarily kind of essential to thought
that
learning is kind of recollection and in
fact the idea of learning as
recollection
which is also uh you know kind of
kantian in the sense that in in kant's
version he talks about
what types of structures need to be
built into the mind
uh in order for us to perceive reality
in a certain way
and in its you know one of its uh you
know
better known um contemporary
instantiations this theory comes to us
by virtue of
uh noam chomsky whose theory of the
universal grammar
says that you know language is not
really taught or learned in the sense
that all languages conform to a basic
structure of universal grammar
that's already built into our cognition
that kind of grows into us
like like puberty and and so this idea
of mathematics
connected with learning but really
connected with this idea of what's
already built
into us what's already there in advance
that idea in advance um
not precisely the same thing as a priori
but connected and so i appropriate this
idea of in advance and i say
there are two fundamental structural
features of modernity
that i induce um uh namely
self-grounding and self-reference
which and you know grounding knowledge
in itself is a kind of drawing upon what
is already there in advance in a
particular way
and by that i mean the the the key
example for that
is uh descartes famous cogito
which grounds knowledge of the world
in the self-certainty of the self who is
the possessor of that knowledge
self-consciousness draws upon what is
already there in advance namely the self
who's doing the knowing
so it's a particular type of
uh uh uh reference to an in advance
because what's already there in advance
is the self who's doing the knowing
and that is the ultimate ground for
knowledge
and so so that's sort of one version
and that's what what grounds what we
call
subjectivity as everything's grounded in
this cartesian subject
but then there's another dimension to
this and that's the object sphere
the subject understands the world as
objects according to this framework
and uh that's where kind of the
newtonian element comes in
and what does the in advance
mathematical have to do with the
so-called
object sphere of newtonian space
and so i go into that and i show how
the particular type of modeling of
the natural world that's a precondition
for the newtonian conception conforms to
this
in advance idea and lends itself to a
very specific type of mathematical
understanding
the ability to grasp the physical world
in
in mathematical terms
and putting those two things together
actually quite interesting because
you have both the subject
and the object sphere and people you
know usually even in colloquial
understanding think of
the subject and the object as to kind of
oppose
things you know one way you can think of
things subjectively other ways you can
think objectively
but actually this shows that both the
subject and the object the subject
object mode of thinking of
the world understanding the world is one
that
on both dimensions
is actually grounded on the specific
understanding of the mathematical as in
advance
and yeah so anyway i can well i was
going to ask you is this related to the
heidegger's concept of jason
like that that is what i would took away
from my conversation with
down to heidegger which is as i
understood it was
sort of the state of being before
becoming aware
is that right um sort of
um so so this is
uh you're referring to heidegger's
concept of
design dozen d-a-s-e-i-n
now this is you know in in very
interesting ways
it's a trans you know it's it's a it's
coin it's a heidigarian
coinage but it draws upon very simple
german words well simple in a certain
sense
um da literally means
there um so
uh yeah vlsind da means we are
there uh da is simply there
and zein is
being being
and so dozen simply means being
there and um
of course that doesn't even begin to
kind of give a sense
of what it means in the heideggerian
context but
being there is it refers to a specific
mode of existing
being a specific mode of existing
in the world and a whole kind of
contextual ecology
that can support a certain way of
existing
in the world i think that um
maybe the context that you're describing
is one that refers to
being in time his first you know major
work
in which there are different kind of
modes of relationship to being there
referring to you know different kind of
levels of awareness and consciousness
and self-awareness so there's like
present at hand ready to hand and so
forth
you know maybe you don't need to get
into all that but the
the term dozy refers to a specific
mode of being and
it's related to heidegger's idea that
man is the shepherd of being in the
sense that
being as such is
transmuted through dozen human beings
special relation to the world is that
they're
kind of the house of being or even a
vessel through which
being expresses itself and that is
kind of the unique feature not
of human beings but of design
human being only only human beings can
act as dazzling but human beings aren't
necessarily dozen
and it's in fact one of heidegger's
concerns
is that precisely the transformation of
man's
being in the world inaugurated by
modernity
and cultivated in you know culminating
in technological modernity
threatens man's capacity to exist
as dazine and simply becomes
another being another
piece of material as it were another
resource in fact he even
invokes the now familiar concept
of human resources
um so hr is in a deep philosophical way
opposed to man's uh uh best mode of
being which is as
dazzling and so i mean this is something
that
you know i've been i'm very busy these
days and
and i haven't really you know talked
about this stuff
for years but ultimately i really would
um like to maybe do a series of lectures
really kind of explaining all of these
things because
i hate the idea that people think of it
as obscurantist or there's nothing there
there's a lot there um i mean i don't
you know i try to be humble but i but i
am a you know
very perceptive person very talented
person i spent a lot of time on this
and i can say that this is you know the
most uh
profound thinker that i've ever um
encountered by far
and has really fundamentally shaped um
my understanding of the world so yeah i
think that that to me
is fascinating and i would like to maybe
talk to you another time and dig down on
this a little bit deeper
and uh i've been reading this book
horribly titled the war for eternity
about about bannon
uh and traditionalism and uh dugan
and his experiences and i'm hearing
echoes of some of those thoughts
uh in this conversation here too so
maybe another time we'll dig deeper into
the philosophy of it i
am fascinated by it but i do know that
we have a very
timely topic to get to
and i was i wanted to give people
context on sort of
how you operate and think and and from
what depth
you're approaching uh today's current
events
and the frame and to show that uh
this is not um willy-nilly or haphazard
or click bait or whatever but this
these thoughts and your ideas and your
perceptions of the world are are
been developed and honed over time in a
very rigorous way
and so you know in the nicest way
possible i say you're very serious
very serious man and what we're going to
talk about here is very serious stuff
um and so i'm going to move us through
your timeline a little bit here
uh you were one of the earliest if not
the only
um tenured or were you tenured uh but
non-tenured professor uh who who
predicted and supported donald trump's
uh
election uh and and then uh after he was
elected you actually did work in the in
the white house for a little bit if you
could just share just a minute or two
about that
it's it's widely known but i'd like to
just you know just touch on it
yeah no it was a great experience um you
know it was it was quite an experience
just
being a professor at duke and being the
only person
there publicly supporting trump and
being the only member of the political
science faculty who correctly predicted
the outcome of the election
that was another thing says you know i
was a part i was a political theorist i
was
you know a quote-unquote philosopher i
was studying heidegger i wasn't supposed
to be the one
to accurately predict the election that
was left to the people
doing you know third four
you know third and fourth rate you know
statistics who claimed to be able to
predict elections based off of it
and so that was that was quite an
amusing thing that
you know i as the political theorist was
the one who did it but
you know just drew upon a kind of
qualitative understanding of
you know where the country was and and
what the country
needed at the time and how trump was
unapologetic which i thought was a very
strong signal and so
and then the other amazing thing was
after i kind of
distinguished myself that way which
really amounts to a performative
resignation letter from
the academy you know it's like there's
just a lot you know there are a lot of
they're good people in there but it's
it's it's really become it's a
profession for
really risk-averse mediocrities plus
legacy boomers who are just kind of
riding off their tenure and you know
rotting away
not doing anything important but it's
it's
it's not it doesn't it's not a place
anymore that can attract
you know big and ambitious souls who
actually want to make a mark
on this planet and so um
so i was ready to leave anyway and um
but amazingly uh you know i had the
well somewhat good fortune uh
to have been you know brought in to the
white house
as a speechwriter and policy aide to the
president of the united states
whom i had gone to such great lengths
and taken some
you know professional risk to support so
that was an amazing thing you know being
in the white house was an amazing thing
you know most of the colleagues were
excellent people and you know i'm still
very friendly with with most people and
and even new people in there so
that was an amazing experience amazing
experience to be able to
write words and you know turns a phrase
and just put concepts
in that reached um tens of millions of
people
uh through through the president uh so
it's you know truly an amazing uh
privilege that i had
i'm very grateful for it and
um yeah i did that for about a year
so it was you know never a dull day as
you can imagine
uh but uh yeah then i left due to uh
due to the fake media running a hit
piece on me
and so i left in a bit of a scandal
um and then um you know that was
you know over two years ago now and so
since then i've remained
very active in politics as an advisor
and an operator behind the scenes as is
in many cases and now um you know very
much
involved with revolver news which is
doing a tremendous job i think on many
fronts in terms of
um giving people information they need
and
filling filling a void from judge report
that
desperately needed to be filled so yeah
you got done dirty
that is for sure uh the fake news media
put out a basically a hit piece you know
what i call the guilt by word smash
where they just say a b and c all
together and even if they're not related
they all get to sort of stink on them
and uh it's unfortunate that you were
targeted in that way but it it does
mean you know that you were uh having an
impact and you were somebody that they
were scared of
and uh in my experience i had something
very similar happened to me where
uh people attacked me online they doxed
me they got me fired and they thought
that they were
silencing me but instead i've only come
back stronger than ever
this time with an army in national reach
now and you're having the same
experience where
you got uh you got cancelled more or
less and uh
instead of just uh picking up your
marbles and running away forever
you decided to uh to gather your
strength and come back even stronger
and uh here you are now uh working with
revolver.news like we've said
you should guys everybody should go
check that out it is uh
got the best analysis as well as a news
aggregation there in the in the old
spirit of drudge but doing it better
uh and so you're you're gathering
strength and you were just on tucker
carlson
the other night maybe two nights ago and
uh it's one of the highest rated tucker
shows i think of all time
uh your internet clips have done
hundreds of thousands if not up to a
million views yet
and uh the interview was four minutes of
absolutely riveting
riveting it wasn't even a conversation
it was you just starting to lay out
what we're facing here yeah tucker was
just like
watching you so intently and then all of
a sudden
you know like the segment was over right
and everybody was like wait wait we just
we're getting to it we're just we're
getting to it so that's
right that's what we're here to talk
about today in depth now is the
the color revolution where does it come
from what is it is it a real thing who's
doing it who's behind it
and uh we've got some time to spread out
and explore these issues so
i'm happy to take it slow and from the
top
and really paint the picture of what
we're facing here in 2020 what the real
threat is what the history of it is
where is it going to go what's it going
to do and so why don't we just start
from
start from the beginning and just sort
of you know
my idea is maybe just describe what it
is or we can start from the genesis
or however you feel comfortable darren
but this is this is what people want to
hear about right now so
color revolution buddy what is it oh
um basically uh
no one was thinking about the
activities against trump in terms of
color revolution
really until this series from revolver
news that begins with
you know the the piece that i was kind
of discussing on tucker's show on norm
eisen which i
you know we need to get into a little
bit that was the third piece
in an installment and by the way there
are even bigger pieces coming up soon
this is going to be an ongoing thing all
the way up to the election and maybe
after
it's maybe the biggest i think it is
kind of
it's the biggest story out there
arguably other than
the covet lockdowns which you know we
might get into as well which i think is
maybe the greatest crime against
uh humanity other than war or genocide
and that's you know really a profound
thing
so other than that i think that
uh this color revolution undertaken
against trump
is the biggest story and really revolver
has the best analysis i just think
that's objectively true
i think your listeners need to go to
revolver.news and start at the beginning
with this story of george kent
and i'll kind of give a little bit of a
summary about this the the the piece is
called
the curious case of george kent and has
a picture of
george kent um just looking suspicious
and uh so who is george kent well
he was a star impeachment witness
against
trump in the impeachment
and um
sorry my computer batteries are going so
we might have to take a quick break
just for me to plug in soon um
george kent was a star impeachment
witness he was
formerly the employee of jovanovic
who is another star impeachment witness
unlike vinman and ivanovic
both bureaucrats tasked
with eastern european affairs who are
going after trump
which is part of the lead here why is it
that
all of these key never trump figures
particularly involved in the impeachment
why is it that all of these people
have something to some diplomatic post
some bureaucratic post
related to eastern europe
vinman jovanovic
all of them this guy george kent
unlike vinman and jovanovic who are both
fired on the basis of their
testimony against the president in this
disgraced and
failed impeachment hoax
george kent was kept on board in the
state department
and even promoted which is unfortunate
george kent at the state department
guess what he does he oversees belarus
interesting if you've been paying
attention
news lately there's a big scandal in
belarus there's this
big bad authoritarian leader and
everyone
said oh there's this champion of
democracy some woman they were trying to
run against him all the the whole
constellation of these
you know ngo state department soros
atlantis
type groups were saying oh this woman is
the great hope of democracy
she's going to win well they did the
election she got like eight percent of
the vote
and she didn't win and
now what they're doing is they're
mobilizing they
being all these atlanticists ngo
organizations
linked to the state department and such
now they're
mobilizing enormous quote-unquote
peaceful protests
so far those peaceful protests haven't
been successful by the way and there
have been pieces coming out
by mainstream media actually complaining
that they're too peaceful
saying they need more manly protesters
to rough things up a little bit and
maybe be more effective
so we'll see how that goes but there are
all of these people
promoted by you know the same no you
know never trump people
tasked with eastern european affairs
are involved in this belarus situation
and have been involved in
similar types of events before back to
our
subject for the moment george kent when
he worked for
jovanovic he was working at the ukraine
station
and he was in fact a deputy political
figure in ukraine during the most
famous color revolution which is the
orange revolution
in ukraine the sources talked to
revolver.news in the state department
have referred to george kent as a
color revolution expert and indeed he is
and so the basic idea the basic
lead was first of all why are all of
these
never trump operatives
involved in this eastern european stuff
that's kind of weird
and isn't there a bizarre similarity in
fact
arresting similarities between
the mode of operation that they use
to attack eastern european leaders they
don't like
and the operations we see now
domestically being deployed against
trump
and do you want you want to describe
those operations now
let's do it yes and the conclusion that
emerges though
is you have it's not just the same
strategies and tactics
it's the same people it's the same color
revolution
professionals whose job it is to run
these
operations to undermine and overthrow
eastern european leaders
they don't like those same people who
don't like trump and view him in the
same category
are using the same playbook against him
so it's the same people
the same playbook now what is the
playbook well
as i pointed out on tucker's show
this figure norm eisen which is a key
architect whose career runs through
every single facet of the color
revolution against trump
wrote a playbook on color revolutions
how to run them
literally called the playbook you can't
make this up
he wrote the playbook literally called
the playbook
and there are several things in this let
me just pull up the
the story so i can so i can read these
passages
uh verbatim to you
um because it's quite something and
maybe we can
um provide a link to the actual playbook
involved but
so this playbook is the color revolution
playbook it's called
the democracy playbook of course they
use democracy
in the same way they use peaceful
protest they care about democracy about
as much as the peaceful protesters
care about non-violence it's totally one
of these things where
they use the word precisely that uh
they're going
against and you know the idea that
they're promoting democracy by
basically shifting the locus
of democratic decision-making onto the
streets in form of protests
and into the courts in the form of
lawfare instead of in the polls which is
actually where real democracy takes
place
just shows you how fundamentally
duplicitous these people are
and until recently they've gotten away
with it this guy that i called out on
tucker's show
in front of millions and millions of
people 4.8 million and counting
is a key figure norm eisen a key figure
in this color revolution against trump
since trump was elected nobody knew who
he was
and all of these left-wing organizations
gave him award after award after award
he is very spoiled he is a very spoiled
little baby never used to hearing you
know unkind word
and then all of a sudden his name was
blast on national
uh television and you can do a search
for his name on twitter and i think he's
been having a very interesting past
couple of days
he's very active on twitter now he's not
so active anymore i think he's plotting
his next move so we'll see
we'll see what he's up to but this is
the author of literally the color
revolution playbook
now let's see what what what things he
says in the playbook well
first of all his justification for why
this playbook is needed
window of opportunity far-right populist
parties many with illiberal tendencies
have gained a toehold or the majority in
23 of 28 eu member states
parliamentary systems the ability of
political opposition and civil society
to operate
gives pro-democracy actors pro-democracy
actors namely
overthrowing democratic results that
they don't like
an urgent window of opportunity to push
back on illiberal activity
before is further entrenched so
basically these same groups are used to
these
operations in eastern europe they view
brexit and the election of trump as a
kind of political
911. those are the twin towers brexit
and election of trump
and they went into emergency mode and
they're saying we need to run the same
playbook
that we use against so-called
authoritarians
in eastern europe against trump and
brand him as an authoritarian
um so let's see some of this uh
playbook okay the playbook references
the ukraine orange revolution which
uh as i mentioned uh george kent
uh was stationed in ukraine during the
orange revolution
he says ukraine's non-violent orange
revolution
non-violent right peaceful it's a term
of art it's a fake word that they use
as part of the playbook ukraine's
non-violent orange revolution of 2004
helped to bring the democratically
elected victor yushenko to power
after widespread election fraud oh wow
so they used election they used a claim
of widespread election fraud to install
someone they like
because the person they didn't like was
originally elected that's interesting
here's another segment from the norm
eisens
playbook normizen um
one of the bullet points is increase
election monitoring capacity
and quote be prepared to use
electoral abuse evidence as basis for
advocacy
interesting let's see what the other
bullet point is
opposition leaders in this case you know
the people going after the so-called
authoritarian they don't like
opposition leaders may also choose to
pursue more
extreme institutional measures available
to them
for example impeachment processes
interesting and or deploy extra
institutional tools
namely protests strikes
or boycotts sounds very very familiar
this is from his playbook on how to
overthrow
foreign governments overseas now the
godfather the originator of the color
revolution model of regime change
his name is gene sharp he's a
fascinating figure everyone should look
into him
norm eisen explicitly acknowledges
his work to be in the tradition of gene
sharp
this is the new gene sharp norm eisen is
the gene sharp for the social
media age whose job it is as a legal
hatchet man
as a mobilizer and so forth as a key
color revolution architect is to ensure
that no political leader
is able to harness the energies
associated with the victory of donald
trump in 2016
and with brexit they want to put the
kibosh
on these populist energies because it
threatens their power
and this is the larger context within
which to understand these operations
leading into 2020.
now just one little point because in the
playbook i mentioned
that norm eisen explicitly references
impeachment processes
along with claims of electoral fraud as
a mechanism
as a color revolution mechanism to
overthrow the target leader
norm eisen wrote 10
articles of impeachment before the
president
even made his call to jill zielenski
impeachment was part of the playbook
before they even had the pretext which
they
cooked up and turned out to be
completely discredited
and a failure so they're running the
playbook against trump
so far their maneuvers have failed
but they're going in for the big time
now
and they're running a full-scale
combination
of massive protests massive
mobilization massive civil disobedience
mostly peaceful of course mostly
peaceful only a few cities get burned
down
only a few houses get torched
you know only only a few uh you know
trump supporters
just get shot dead in cold blood in the
street only a few it's mostly peaceful
what they have in store for you is
mostly peaceful
and what they have in store should their
cipher figure joe biden be elected
well i can guarantee you they have in
store mostly peaceful future for you and
your family
american people they have a mostly
peaceful idea
you know uh so so these people are
are very disgusting and they their
playbook that they have
involves massive mobilization massive
protests combined with a law fair
strategy
and norm eisen is a key architect here
they're finding every single avenue that
imaginable to make sure
that the 2020 election is decided on the
streets
and in the courts and not in the polls
because
the polls the only place that they don't
have an advantage
they control everything else so they
want to do everything they can to make
sure
that it's on the streets in the courts
not in the polls
and as i you know as i uh kind of want
to say
uh is that you know these people the
people like
norm eisen in particular are doing
everything they can to ensure that the
american people
are never able to meddle in their own
elections again
the american people are not supposed to
meddle in their own elections
that's bad that's naughty that's
populism
it's populism when people actually have
a say
in their destiny it's democracy when
shadowy legal hatchet men like norm
eisen
control us that's democracy democracy is
norm eisen's boot on your neck forever
in a mostly peaceful fashion
so um that's that's just the game here
and
you know it would be nice if we had the
chess pieces in play
to you know prevent it in a robust
manner that you know we
really should have been acting on this
years ago but you know better late than
never at least we know what the playbook
is it's literally called the playbook we
know it's author
and that is normizen and um
we have an idea as to what their
strategy is going into 2020
so you know sunlight is disinfectant
even though it's kind of a cliched
concept
and i'm uh you know deeply grateful that
this color revolution framework is now
part of the common conversation
pretty much thanks to these three
articles from revolver.news
and i really have to say everybody
watching this
read those three articles it's the
curious case of george kent
who as far as i'm aware still has his
job at the state department remarkably
enough
the second one is on the transition
integrity project
and the third is on normizen as like i
said there are many more to come
um we're going to be covering this
in detail and
in all of its explosive dimensions going
all the way to
the election day you know everyone's
reading us now
everyone in the white house many many
people throughout the administration
all the right people are paying
attention it's just a matte it's just an
issue of
acting on this information because you
know these guys have been planning
and it looks like we lost darren there
uh i suspect he will be back in just a
minute
i'm going to just continue on for a
little bit here the
what darren has brought up uh is a great
example of how
the trump administration is not only is
not just
in power in the united states government
and doing what it wants to do
the united's the donald trump
administration is actually a
fighting the government itself you know
people have been calling it the deep
state
it is the uni party it is the democrats
and
the republicans of old together who are
basically forming a corporate cabal that
does not have the interests of the
american citizens
at heart and it's interesting to see
that these tactics that were developed
abroad the playbook that was created by
norm eisen was used in ukraine and
belarus
and it is something that is now being
used on
american citizens domestically and that
is a fascinating highlight of how
the trump administration is really an
insurgency
uh it is an insurgency against the
uh the the existing uniparty
welcome back darren the existing
uniparty uh
and uh it's important to keep in mind
that trump you know we all kind of wish
that trump could
go in and wave a magic wand and
uh affect all the change that he wants
to to to do and all the reforms and
and sort of do the whole maga agenda
that he was launched by a network right
because this is a network
uh candidate network presidency he was a
an outsider a revolutionary basically a
weapon that was launched into government
and it's it's important to realize that
he is constantly
fighting a struggle on the inside uh
from people who ostensibly report to him
within the executive branch
uh from people that are supposed to be
uh carrying out his orders uh and
carrying out his agenda
but instead you know he is fighting not
only
the people uh you know on the streets
and and blm
and antifa and all this but also
internally and so darren what i wanted
to do was tie together
uh this comparison between us in the
state department utilizing the playbook
in
foreign elections abroad and in foreign
countries abroad
so we're sort of like the outside
invading force there
right uh by by subverting the elections
in these other countries
but now we're using these same
strategies and tactics and operations
on ourselves domestically and what is
this what does it say
that if our own government is using
these sort of anti-democratic measures
on our own democratic process
what does that tell us about the nature
and condition
of politics in our government you know
in general and who is really ruling us
and where do they get their authority
and how do they maintain
it right now that's a great question and
i think
you know it's it's a process that really
began
um you know in 2015 um
when you know trump announces candidacy
and conducted a very unconventional
type of campaign that you know shocked
everyone and certainly shocked
these people like norm eisen into terror
you know
one of the great clips that everyone
needs to see
i think it was uh broken by a great
uh tech reporter alam bakari at
breitbart
and it was the entire c-suite
of google going absolutely nuts the day
after
trump ran the entire c-suite of google
some of them were crying i think there
was
there's a woman that was crying they
they had a hug
session they made everyone hug because
they were so emotionally traumatized by
the election outcome
these weren't just random employees this
is the whole c-suite
sitting in a row and going one by one
siri adam
about how devastated they were the
election
and how this will never happen again
and they weren't the only ones every
single pal like
when when trump ran in 2016
he ran against the coordinated
opposition
of every single powerful institution in
the country
of big tech of the republican
establishment the democrat establishment
the clinton dynasty the bush dynasty
many corporations the military
industrial complex
every single powerful institution was
against him and he won
because he had popular support he was uh
you had the support of the people but
they kind of were caught
slipping as they say they would they
weren't expecting that and so
after that happened is okay we're going
on full lockdown mode
um no and pun very much intended
they're going on full lockdown mode
locking down
the internet and now locking down people
in their houses and shutting down the
economy
they're doing everything they're pulling
out everything to ensure that
this can never happen again and it's an
entirely different story actually
if you haven't had him on i recommend
you have on
alan bakari okay good
and he's coming up he's got a new book
coming out i think it's called deleted
and it is a deep dive into all of the
issues around tech the cabal
there are limits on free speech their
attempts to manipulate what we know
what we think what we feel and uh
influence the election as well yeah
definitely he's coming up later
a great guy and and basically what's
happened is
the internet that existed in 2015
doesn't exist anymore and just the
profundity of that is it's just
it's incredible this is the internet
does not exist
in the same form that it existed in 2015
and um and
it's just because the internet
effectively harvested
and channeled the energies associated
with the brexit victory
and with the trump victory and it gave
the people a kind of voice to combat
you know the oligarchs that want to keep
control over things and just
you know prevent people from not only
having a say but having any
real understanding of what's going on it
has to all come from their organs of
distribution
and you see them calling for that now uh
hillary clinton just tweeted
yesterday that you know basically
threatening
you know all of the big tech firms to
prevent so-called disinformation leading
up to the election
so that is to ensure that you know
whatever narrative that they want to
present
is effectively the narrative in a very
chaotic and likely contested election
scenario
where information is uh crucial
so yeah it's it's very disturbing
and just getting back to what you're
saying about like the power structure
generally
is just as we're all like now required
to wear
masks i say kind of the
metaphorical mask of what america
is and who you know kind of runs it how
it's run
that mask is slipping the power
structure is
basically revealing itself and in a way
this is positive and
clarifying but in a way it's
they don't even they think
they don't even need the illusions that
they used to rely upon in the 20th
century
and so forth they used to need illusion
they needed
kind of false narrative to make things
sound good of
democracy and freedom and liberal
democracy
and rule of law and all of these you
know fake
concepts that really mean in those
contexts the precise
opposite of what they say they don't
really need the pretext of america being
a free society anymore
they can just lock us down and they've
showed that they can do it
they can just lock us down they can call
upon
this you know virus which is a real
virus don't get me wrong this isn't
you know some weird conspiracy thing
like it's not a real virus it's a real
virus it's deadly people who are in
vulnerable categories
need to take precautions it's you know
deadlier than
a severe flu although not by much
but the idea of shutting down the entire
economy
indefinitely over this is unprecedented
and so absurd it
goes into the militias and um
this is maybe like one of the most
important studies that
revolver.news did by three
phds two of whom uh in economics
who have to publish pseudonymously
because this
unfortunately the nature of the academy
so if you question this kind of thing
you threaten a large amount of uh
grant money and that's just
unfortunately the nature of that
of that profession is corrupted by money
just like everything else
but the analysis speaks for itself this
is
on revolver.news the analysis
was retweeted by the president and
basically it does
a rundown on the damage of these
lockdowns
and shows that the lockdowns have been
far more deadly
than the disease and i use deadly in a
real way they've
they've led to the loss of more life
years
by a factor of 10 than the virus itself
and you know i encourage people to go
look at it it's very rigorous it's or
the methodology is quite plain
but just conceptually what your readers
or
your listeners should know is this idea
of disaggregating the economy from
health
is totally false it's totally false
because
economic devastation
leads necessarily to health consequences
there's an established economic
literature out there
showing quite conclusively that any
marginal increase
in say unemployment leads to marginal
increases in health effects either from
suicide either from not having the money
to get necessary medical treatment
and so forth so there's no such thing as
damage to mere economy
or prioritizing people's health over the
economy
the economy is people's health you
cannot disaggregate
people's lives from their livelihood
and it's it's just very it's a very
simple important thing that you would
think if we were a serious country
we would employ serious kind of public
policy analysis
but and and it just a like a a
politically
uncontroversial example that uh you know
given
in the revolver.news report is in
transportation policy
so let's say that you know you
you just like we're basically shutting
down the entire economy to pro
you know to prevent you know any nine
year
90 year old with seven comorbidities
from you know to prolong his life for
another week
let's just assume that that's you know
the right policy so
let's look at air travel and say we want
to make sure we're going to do
everything we can to ensure that you
know there are no
air accidents we're willing to impose
any regulation imaginable
and so you say okay we're going to we're
going to do all these regulations this
is from a real case
we can do all these regulations but
regulations are not
uh free they translate into higher costs
for air travel
so now air travel is prohibitively
expensive for most people
and so a bunch of people take
alternative forms of transportation
that are far more dangerous than air
travel was
before the regulations were instated so
whereas you may have saved life years
looking simply at air travel the
transportation industry at large
you're leading to a lot more deaths yeah
yeah i think i think that there's a
major deficit of second order thinking
going on
all over the country and uh you know
back in
february when this was starting to break
you know i i was very active on twitter
about it
and you know i i saw the shutdowns
coming i didn't know if it was the right
thing or the wrong thing and i still
don't necessarily have a position on the
virus
i've always been focused more on like
what's going to happen to us like
logistically speaking and it's clear
that we're living through a national
tragedy of some kind right
now one for the history books for sure
that
certainly it has second or a failure
second-order thinking
to it but what i find fascinating also
in the context of this larger
conversation we're having about the the
insurgency
trump's insurgency that the counter
insurgency from the deep state
uh this this sort of who's the
revolutionary here
there there has been a lot of first
second and third order thinking that
goes into the preparation and planning
for the resistance to trump so by that i
mean
there has been a conditioning right
where to take away
uh you know some liberties start
infringing on free speech
start training and guiding people to
think that they don't have the right to
just speak up or have their own thoughts
or even start training people to think
that your internal alarm
instincts of when you're in a negative
or just uncomfortable situation is
something that should be listened and
honored right like that's a
element of anti-racist philosophy
and whatnot or ideology religion
whatever
uh where they tell you if you're
uncomfortable just ignore that your
internal alarm bells are are wrong you
shouldn't listen to it
so i think that there's actually a lot
of deeper uh second and third order
thinking going on here as people are
trying to manipulate our country and to
manipulate
and and and basically control us so that
this trump revolution uh is is
unsuccessful and fails and i want to tie
this all back together because
you were saying that they before there
was even
a notion of an impeachable uh offense
that they were already
just planning how they were going to
impeach him right like this is
this is a systematic approach
to reversing the electoral will
of the people and they have the support
of uh the the deep state the democratic
party
the leading candidates the corporations
the foot soldiers on the ground
academics that are pushing critical race
theory and have been pushing
radical feminism and intersectionality
for for for years and years and years
now
and so all this appears to be cohesive
and comprehensive um do you
think and let's not get too out there
you know if you've got evidence or or or
well thought out positions but do you do
you
think is there a central source
of this coordinated effort against the
trump revolution
or is it just the spontaneous reaction
of people who are in power being afraid
that they're
losing power like how does this work is
it directed is it emergent
like it seems so thoughtful but is it
all accidental like how does it work
darren
well i mean you know obviously i'm not
uh
you know i i don't have any videotapes
of their secret meetings at least not
yet
but i but i think that we can engage in
some kind of
informed speculation as to how this
going on first of all
i think the color revolution thesis one
of its advantages
is it shows that there's already a
built-in network of people who are used
to operating in a particular way
namely you know this nexus of
so-called atlantis it involves like the
atlantic
council there are many many ngos many of
which
have democracy in the title so for
instance one of the ngos
is called the transatlantic democracy
working group
sort of an umbrella group for all of
these kind of color revolution regime
change organizations
it's run believe it or not by normizen
and it's a it's a group that's been very
active in promoting the color revolution
in belarus
you know and the so-called peaceful
protesters in belarus
and one twitter commenter said hey i it
sounds like you're talking about america
and the the twitter account for this
organization said oh
let's hope we're not talking about the
the ghost of america's future
and so very explicitly making this
connection
um so i think that there's a relevant
point that there's already a
network an infrastructure and a playbook
in place so you don't really and you
know a particular stake that they hold
in power structure in the united states
so you have
a lot of elements there and maybe in
fact the color revolution model wouldn't
be the optimal model even to go against
trump it's just that
what they know and what they're used to
and so you so so what you have and you
know
i'm not suggesting that this is the only
faction the american
power structure is not you know it's
it's i think you can think of it
profitably
as a kind of mafia and just like the
mafia there's
you know there are different mafia
families there are different
factions now they don't always agree
with each other sometimes they disagree
vehemently sometimes they even go to
you know into some kind of metaphorical
war but they're all kind of
they coordinate for certain purposes and
particularly when they have a common
enemy
and so it's not monolithic they're
different factions
one of the factions is the faction
that's this atlanticist
group and is all the constellation of
ngos that are kind of
color revolution oriented the atlantic
council
german marshall fund very much linked
with the state department
whose geopolitical priority has been
eastern europe and again it's like why
use all this weird russia stuff against
trump that in fact there's
like you could use a lot of other
countries if you wanted to tarnish trump
why russia does it seems weird
that's the playbook they're used to
because they're used to doing this stuff
in eastern europe and using russia as
part of their model
propaganda model so they're just using
what they're used to so it
it's like a copy paste almost copy paste
color revolution
from all the stuff that they've been
doing in eastern europe
that they use oh this particular eastern
european leader is a russian stooge
oh this person's in cahoots with putin
it's literally a copy and paste into
trump where it makes
absolutely no sense and so i think the
the color revolution explains
part of it and of course there's just a
broader power structure it involves
you know the media it involves um
you know just large economic interests
that
you know might be threatened by you know
or maybe tied economically with china
and so they don't like trump's china
stuff
like there are different components to
it but i think you can kind of get an
intuitive sense for how it would exist
simply by noting that you know trump
came into power with
really kind of no elite constituency no
faction really kind of on his side
and so um just the idea that someone
could come in kind of out of nowhere and
disrupt things like that
is worrisome to the whole power
structure every faction even if
the factions themselves don't get along
on everything
and in the case of the color revolution
you have the playbook in place you have
the network in place
and you have the institutions in place
and of course a friendly media
ready to converge on any narrative that
that they pick up on so
it doesn't have to even be
conspiratorial
in that kind of smoke-filled room type
sense
yeah so i get confused when i start
trying to think about
uh who is the revolutionary right now
right so on one hand critical race
theories clearly anti-founding
clearly anti-american tradition it has a
contrary view of justice
uh one of taking from others rather than
considering everybody to be an
individual
and a whole there's a distribution
distributive element of it
and and it certainly uh is not uh
in the same spirit of uh equality under
the law
and so i can see how critical race
theory intersectionality social justice
warriors whatever
the woke walkers that people have called
them if that they
are are revolutionary to the idea of
america
but but in this case
uh it feels as though they may be foot
soldiers
or at least co-opted to be in this case
uh of a counter revolution of a counter
insurgency which is targeted at the
trump maga you know faction which is the
actual
sort of revolutionaries against this
mono
party and the deep state and the
converged institutions so
is it is it really as confusing as it is
to me as to like who's in power
but who's in charge and who are who's
revolting and who's
fighting a revolution it seems so muddy
to me
well i mean i don't i don't know how if
it's even that muddy i mean because
because you can look at these groups
like
antifa black lives matter who in some
way might
present themselves as um
challenging the power structure and yet
every single major corporation the
country
has uh expressed support for the
rhetoric
the false rhetoric of systemic racism
animating these violent movements
and in many cases like it was a standard
sort of
ransom money many of the corporations
pledged 100 million dollars which is
kind of the agreed upon number through
various black lives
matter type organizations in the
aftermath the george floyd incident
so the idea that you have you know
in the entirety of corporate america
supporting you you have all the
corporate media supporting you
you have the uh upper echelons
of the um security services
supporting you you have you know mattis
supporting you
google big tech censoring all of your
enemies you're not even allowed to say
anything positive about
or even defensive about kyle rittenhouse
on facebook
you're not allowed to organize you know
counter protests of black lives matter
on facebook
you're allowed to organize black lives
matter on facebook
you're not allowed to fundraise for you
know anti-black lives matter stuff you
you are allowed so like so if you look
at what the power structure is and what
they're supporting
i think it's actually quite clear that
these you know blm
antifa type groups are completely
uh uh instruments of the power structure
and operate as a kind of paramilitary
shock droop force
to intimidate and crush the one truly
insurgent
demographic which is basically
um the american middle class and i might
even say like the white middle class but
maybe the
middle class more broadly is the only
kind of
you know potentially insurgent force
standing behind
standing between the kind of the
oligarch
and consolidated power system and
complete control
so uh that's you know pretty plainly
what it is
and it's it is a development it wasn't
always this way
i mean i think these organizations have
always been
um you know disgusting and destructive
but
as you know recently as you know
remember the seattle
issue and and that was uh you know a lot
of the same you know
the groups have the same provenance of
you know the antifa type groups
um protesting the wto meeting
uh in in seattle so they were actually
engaging in violent protests to protest
basically globalist free free trade
policies
and as recently as um you know the obama
era you had something similar
organized in the occupy wall street and
they were challenging you know i
i don't agree with their approach but
at least in that case you can say that
they were going up against a real
kind of power faction whereas now
they've been
completely uh
neutered they've they've they've
undergone a kind of
reassignment surgery as it were
[Laughter]
well what's what strikes me from this
conversation you see most
of those like the the antifa people are
you know there's a lot of
transsexuals i'm not saying there's
anything wrong with that but there are a
lot of transsexuals
and i think like even metaphorically
they've you know
the antifa is a post-op organization
because
they they used to they've always been
bad but they used to
you know actually go against powerful
institutions and now they're just
completely the instrument
of you know broad swaths of the american
ruling class
what's fascinating about this framing is
that
the implication here is that the white
middle class or the middle class more
broadly as you say
has already lost we lost at some point
years ago oh yeah that's that's not gone
yeah yeah we lost big time yeah and
and we lost years ago and it's only now
that we're actually able to mount a
serious
uh you know fight back against what has
been happening basically since what like
the mid 80s or so
or going back to the 60s even and so
it's fascinating like you said earlier
that whenever they say
you know the democracy handbook it's
actually the anti-democracy handbook
and in this case we're talking they're
saying that they're revolutionaries on
the street
uh black lives matter antifa chanting
about being revolutionaries and
anti-anti-fascism
and anti-big corporatist power and
whatever
um but at the same time man you like
dude i've been down at lafayette square
right where mayor mayor uh bowser
bloomberg's
dog named it black lives matter plaza
and then the street name says black
lives matter they wrote black lives
matter on the street
in letters you can see from outer space
and then all the buildings around it are
draped
in you know first class first rate
graphic design corporate sponsored black
lives matter
flags and banners and then they're on
the street
in like an organized military formation
fighting against
the police there banging their war drums
with their banners flown on the
buildings on the street
named after them with this their name
written right on the street
and yet they're saying that they're the
revolutionaries and so when we put it in
this context it becomes
absolutely absurd yeah
and and it makes them even more uh
hypocritic
uh hypocritical but also stooges many of
them are just stooges i believe
uh whipped up you know the average guy
on the street protesting this stuff
doesn't
doesn't have any of the knowledge about
what's really going on or the background
or the history or who's pulling the
strings or whatever they've just been
agitated you know they've been agitated
and so the real uh revolutionaries here
are the ones that are talking about the
founders vision
and free speech and justice and the
constitution
and and very much in the same vein as
claremont institute in their academic
thrust
uh somehow we're now the revolutionaries
we lost the war
uh the institutions have been taken over
and
donald trump was somebody that they
poop-hooed
and discounted and we voted him into
office
to blow all this up and to take take
back the country
make america great again perfect right
and so as soon as that happened they've
been running this playbook and what i
want to talk about now
is what do we here the two things i want
to talk about on the way out here in the
next half hour so
what can we expect moving forward
then what do we do to combat it
yeah um well what can we expect
that's that's difficult to say i mean i
think in the next
several months are going to be extremely
uh chaotic i think we can
probably expect some kind of contested
election scenario like
you know what they're engineering like
how can imagine that that they
if they're they're engineering a
situation where
you know you have to have unprecedented
mail-in ballots uh you know
a procedure that's fraught with just
mistakes forget about the fraud it's
just
you know do we really trust the
competence
of the people who would be in charge in
that we're we're not a competent country
we're a fundamental we're an incompetent
country
we can't do anything and little and so
we decide out of nowhere to
uh undergo this massive mail-in
thing that's sure to engineer
some kind of dispute and of course like
i say the disputes go to the courts
and the left controls the courts they
control the courts they control the
streets they control
everything but the poles and so they've
engineered it very well to say okay well
there's this big deadly virus that's
killing
you know uh that's killing 95 year olds
with
eight comorbidities there's this deadly
virus killing
in 95 year olds with eight comorbidities
we need to not only shut down the entire
economy but we need to introduce
a mode of voting that we don't really
know how to do that's
sure to result in a complete you know
just cluster
and then we'll conveniently go to the
courts and
to provide additional pressure we have
massive street mobilizations
forget about the fact that we're totally
able to mobilize hundreds of thousands
of people and demonstrations
and they're not gonna get this deadly
disease only the only people getting the
disease are people going in the polls
not being good boys and girls and voting
by by mail
that's you know if you go to the polls
you'll get the disease if you go to the
demonstration
um you won't get the disease because the
uh the uh the laws of epidemiology
are uniquely suspended to accommodate
the political project
of trump's enemies it's amazing how it
goes it's a special
epidemiology embraced by dr fauci
and so you you have this situation
that's you know very clear now how it's
going to develop
it's going to develop into the courts of
chaos it's going to be mass
mobilizations i think you know one of
the only
things that trump should do at this
point is if they're going to be mass
mobilizations into the streets
particularly in washington
he needs to send his people there too
send
you know the trucker groups send the
bikers and the union people
and just like the mega like tea party
people
get a big crowd get you know make the
physical presence known
otherwise you're just seeding the
territory to the enemy
you need to put the pieces in place they
need to be there so i think there needs
to be
physical mobilization on the right there
needs to be
you know a real kind of strategy on how
to deal
with um anticipated problems for
instance
you have certain swing states with
democrat governors
you want to make sure that you're not
going to have these people
you know pursue like faithless elector
strategies
what what what are the rules that they
have as to whether you can be a faithful
or faithless elector
that can make a decisive difference you
need to have a strategy
a legal strategy for how to deal with
that if
if the norm eisen and his groups
try to convince these states to pursue
faithless electors
which by the way he tried to do in 2016
unsuccessfully
but it's very it's it's already on his
mind he tried it once
i'm sure he'll try it again you have to
you know prepare a situation like you
know the the election will need to be
certified by the house of
representatives controlled by democrats
what are you going to do about this you
have to
you know anticipate all of those you
know every single institution that could
play a role in this and
come up with some kind of best strategy
as to what you're going to do about it
and ideally kind of get ahead of it
um so that's for that's for the election
2020. you know going forward it's going
to be a
a deeply unpleasant
uh thing if um biden wins
because he's probably just gonna you
know collapse the next day and then we
have president kamala
then god help us it's gonna be horrible
you better
you know renew your passports if you
need to and maybe just get the hell out
of here because i think you know kamala
would be a real disaster
um but um in any case i think
um you know we do need to start thinking
about
also the limits to populism because this
game of
just having the people and not having
any elite constituency is really kind of
not
panning out very well and so there needs
to be kind of a longer term
strategy to cultivate and facilitate
an emerging elite to supplant
the old and corrupt
ruling class that has proven itself to
be such a
disastrously poor custodian of this once
great country and they've turned it in
to something worse than a joke and so i
think
there we need to start thinking about
the cultivation of real uh talent
and you know kind of uh
political organization and political
mode of communication and just
being that um is
highly attractive to um
members of a potential emerging elite
and kind of strategy to place these
people in various
sectors of power including the tech
sector the legal sector
uh government and so forth and i think
there's been a lot of this going on you
know it
hasn't been a lot of time you know it's
it's only been like you know less than
four years since
2016 and so all this stuff is in the
works but
um that is you know i think what's
necessary to
kind of a longer term um strategy
of winning is that you know you can't
you it's it's great to have
the people um you know the people as in
you know kind of the masses popular
support but
um uh you know for better or worse the
reality is that
so much of winning is is the inside game
no and uh yeah yeah so a couple of
things come to mind as you're saying
that um
one is that i always had the feeling in
2015 that trump
was perfectly suited to the moment um
and sort of rode a wave uh
it it remains to me to be seen
if he is capable of creating the wave
or being very proactive
in shaping the reality as it needs to be
rather than
being the right man the right place the
right time with the right message and
the right social media power and the
right everything
whereas now like we need him to be an
institution builder
and a strategist and a bureaucrat in
some ways
and i i wonder about an emerging
elite class funny to say that in the
context of populism but i hear what
you're saying and i totally understand
it's the people that are actually
doing things to replace the other people
that are doing things
there's a great risk right now in
as you know and as i know in being a
public supporter of the president how
crazy that is
right but there's a great risk for that
and uh i would like to have seen
a little bit more signaling from the
administration that they're going to be
willing to support people who are
willing to take risks
on their behalf which is on behalf of
the mission of the country
and so i wonder if that is going to
if people are going to be willing to
take the risks necessary in order to go
out on that
that limb in order to do the right thing
and so that ties me to my next question
which is
who is handling all this for the
president right now he has got
a lot of things on his plate aside from
this particular
issue which to me is the most
fundamental one but like
who is game planning this who is
strategizing this
who is in charge who's been delegated to
to to fight back against the scholar of
revolution the insurgency that we're
seeing
and to make sure that we don't not only
hopefully win this election but like
not have the country fall apart in the
process
right well that's a good question and i
think you know like any with anything
um any response to this would have to
come at the direction
of the president so you know i know
you know the president is a regular
reader
of revolver and he's tweeted out at
least our covet study and just a general
endorsement
but um i really hope that he
takes to heart um the color revolution
thesis that we're promoting and um take
some
actions to um counter it and
some of the actions i've described and
other actions
you know could it could be undertaken
but maybe not
kind of publicly given away but there uh
you know there there is stuff that you
can do but
it's not an optimal situation you know
it's like
if anyone plays chess you know that you
know you can get yourself
mired in a strategically disadvantageous
position
and even if you play perfectly you're in
trouble depending on the skill level of
your opponent
and what had to have been done really is
from day one taken years to put the
pieces in place
in the department of justice in the
state department
and various other agencies so that when
you're
confronted with a situation like this
you have
full and immediate authority over the
executive apparatus
which doesn't which doesn't exist now
right so why doesn't
why does norm eisen still is norma eisen
still in the state department or is that
georgetown
george kent george kent why is george
kent still there
who's cleaning house this is what i
don't understand and this would be my
number one criticism of the president
love the president want him re-elected
know that he's essential to
basically the stability and future of
the country but at the same time dude
it's like
why is that guy still there why why not
more action
why i'd love to know and i
um i think that it's
very very very likely that uh pompeo is
aware
of the george kent piece and so you know
it's a
i think it would be a question that i'd
like to ask
secretary pompeo's to you know why
um george kent who is this color
revolution professional
who was a star impeachment against
a witness against president was promoted
subsequent to his attack on the
president
and particularly in light of the
disturbing
connection between all of these eastern
european
bureaucrats these bureaucrats charged
with
meddling and undermining elections in
eastern europe
are running this same playbook against
trump
it seems deeply disturbing that someone
like that
would remain in that position i don't
think you know george kent
is not really a mastermind
of anything um and norm eisen is really
a much more important figure so i'm
and but norm eisen is you know you know
openly a creature of the left
um but yeah i mean what you draw
attention to is
is a larger problem which is a kind of a
personnel
problem and it's been a problem that has
um had largely negatively affected
uh the trump administration and has
created a lot of disloyal people and
saboteurs even
installed in positions of great
influence and power
to the detriment of the president's
agenda and the president
and the country and everyone who
supports
the president and who have you know
done so at direct
personal sacrifice and professional
sacrifice
yeah i agree uh the the struggle that he
faces on a daily basis
not only fighting the big bad fight but
also
internally the deep state people in his
organization at first it was
it was the gop itself you know with uh
his first chief of staff and all that
stuff i mean it just
when you look back and you think about
who we had in place at the beginning and
i'm thinking about guys like
bannon flynn you and anton
to name four uh i would have really
loved to see what would have happened
there
and that was the real
i want to say the intellectual
horsepower behind
the maga movement and what trumpism
means
because that's what i think people don't
really understand and the liberal media
for sure does not get this
all they do is they keep saying that the
maga you know movement is
evangelicals and dumb white dudes and
hicks and whatever
but but uh with all due respect to those
voting blocks
those folks were gonna vote red no
matter what they were that's just gop
they're going to vote red no matter what
the people that swung the election
on trump's behalf in my opinion democrat
to deplorable is a version of that
my book describes us indepthly but our
intelligent
forward people who understand the
philosophical questions at play here
today
that understand the connection between
our government and our humanity
and our expression of history and it was
really those folks like bannon and anton
and you uh and flynn who understand that
who understood the world as it was and
believed in america and america and
power and the might
and the future the beauty of america and
then they were
you guys were all tooken out all taken
out at the beginning
right yeah and
you know i what happened to me was
not in the you know scale of what
happened to poor flynn like that was
that was a
that's a horrible situation but but i
think uh
generally like the point about this
cancel culture issue is that you know
people
ask sometimes you know
just don't even understand how i could
have been
attacked so viciously for something
so ridiculous and trivial and
it's like the the cancel culture is not
an issue of how offensive you are it's
an issue of how effective you are
it has nothing to do with how offensive
you are you can be very offensive
if you're not effective they'll probably
leave you alone unless they can use you
to hurt someone who is effective um
it's all about being effective and
talented
and these commissars these journalist
commissars
who have no talent who have never had an
original thought
in their minds who exist in
the sewer and they belong in the sewer
and in fact
you know their whole lineage is is
really sewage
when you look into their family history
their whole families are sewage
and when you so when you look into these
literal
trash people who've never contributed
anything we've never had an original
idea
never done anything brave and whose job
it is
basically to sit around and scroll
twitter and to you know poke their noses
into places and
you know basically sniff the farts of
people who are far
superior to them um you
you you know you you have you know a
situation where these
pathetic people are able to
have some kind of effect um simply by
you know low level gossip and guilt by
association games
i think that's kind of coming to an end
um i think people kind of understand
that it's a joke
and i think people understand that all
these journalists by the way
these journalists are very dirty people
and they have a lot of skeletons too and
i think it could be really interesting
to look into their histories and figure
out
what's going on with them you know
because there are a lot of
there are a lot of very interesting
things there are a lot of things that i
happen to know about some of these
journalists
that would shock people so um you know
they have a lot of skeletons too
and some of them it's just an issue of
karma some of these people some of these
hit peace people
have generated a lot of bad karma and so
that's all i'll say about that but
it's really bad karma um so and and the
american people hate them
the american people hate these
journalists
um really because they are the enemies
of the people their
their job is not to report the truth
their job is to suppress their rebellion
and that's why i call them commissars
that's their that's our whole job is to
suppress the rebellion
and anyone who might stir up you know
feelings that could animate
confidence of patriotic americans and
countries so they are enemies of the
people
and the american people do hate them for
good reason it's totally okay to hate
them because they are
hateful people but you shouldn't just
hate you should also have contempt for
them and understand that
their minds are trash and even
understand that
their entire family lineages in many
cases are trash
and so they operate out of uh resentment
um and that's basically the american
journalist
class yeah yeah
many of the yeah i you know i was going
to say something offensive
no it's good i like the offense i also
uh
i've been rereading rules for radicals
and
and and it just it it has given
me a fresh look at the co at the context
in which
how people attack ridicule is really
important and valuable
and if you if you guys people wonder why
you see ridicule out there and get in
utilized i mean it is an effective tool
to
to delegitimize your opponent but
when you say that the journalists are
the commissars
where they're supposed to be the ones
bringing you the truth
but in reality they're bringing you the
lies
it's like the revolutionaries in the
street who are really
the people who are fighting to maintain
the establishment
um up is down left is right
america is america whatever like
everything is twisted and backwards and
upside down
which is why conversations like this
which is why the work that you're doing
at revolver is so important
uh which is why the social media network
that evolved around trump uh
and helped him get elected is so crucial
uh
you said that the internet had changed
uh from
2015 fundamentally so
can you just describe a little bit about
what you mean by that and then
but but contextualize it with 2020. like
we know that 2015 and 2016 the internet
and social media had a big part to do
with the election
huge part and now it's basically gone i
mean
the alan will give you the full run down
into all this but you know
basically everything effective has been
blown out of the water
and for the few people that remain it's
had a profound chilling effect
because they don't want to get blown out
like everyone else
um you know facebook is you know
clamping down on everyone um
youtube completely censoring people
blowing out their accounts
algorithmically uh demoting
them you know twitter obviously you know
people getting
uh blasted off of twitter
and um and yeah in google like if you
just use the google search
is it's a google is a great company as a
just
truly amazing search algorithm and now
for
basically anything remotely political
it's
it's virtually unusable um
and so it's like it's a dangerous thing
it's not just about politics it's about
this issue where everyone's been trained
to think
of the internet as this kind of
ethereal repository of information
that's
you know separate from any
necessity of physical space you don't
need to possess
information because it's stored in the
cloud
but the information stored in the cloud
is subject to all kinds of manipulation
so i think
you know for people who are know about
bitcoin in your audience there's you
know big mantras like if you don't
have it you don't own it if you don't
have the key you don't own it you
you know store your own you don't use a
or you don't use a
a third party people need to start
thinking about that with information and
you know
uh there are all kinds of interesting
subjects you try to look them up
you'll find a graveyard of dead links
and you know so people need to start
saving information treating it not like
oh
it's on the internet therefore it'll be
there it's like there's this
there's the theory that you know in the
internet is forever
actually that's not true anymore in fact
the
sensors have even put pressure on the
wayback machine
to not catalog the stuff that they
censor because they don't want people to
have a work around to use the wayback
machine
the internet is not forever the the uh
they've been censoring
stuff about uh the the covid lockdowns
on the wayback machine
and so the internet is forever
may apply to that offensive joke you
told 20 years ago but it doesn't apply
to crucial information
relevant to the biggest policy disaster
in americans history which is the
coveted lockdowns
funny how that works the internet is
forever
applies to that you know
sexist remark you made 20 years ago it
doesn't apply
to any official narrative that the
people control this country are trying
to shove down your throat
and that's and that's that's the kind of
that democracy that uh mostly peaceful
democracy that
norm ivan uh has in mind for us
it sounds like it's like conspiracy
tinfoil stuff to think that google's
manipulating search results but i had an
experience um a couple months ago where
i typed in jack murphy live into
google nothing of my own
work came back nothing my website wasn't
there it was
gone and i called my uh tech guy who is
an
internet og he understands what's going
on he's been doing this 20 years
he starts digging into it and we're
looking and we're like man i don't
understand
then like that everything came back
so as we were watching it everything
came back and then
later that day the federalist and
breitbart and all these other people
came out with stories being like holy
our
our results have been deleted off of off
of google
and we're just not in the search results
so it wasn't it didn't just happen to me
it happened to a lot of other people
were all flagged
and they tested or had an algorithm go
crazy or whatever it was but they
tested a feature that they have where
they can just
eliminate a huge group of of sites out
of the search results
period done gone and we watch them
actually do it and restore it in real
time
so i know i know that this is a real
thing
and uh and i use bing now for everything
just throwing that out there
like it's not even because they admit
that they do it they
look at the ceo of youtube which is
under you know the same parent company
as google
they admit it and they're proud of it
and they want they want to figure out
ways they can do more and
it's really it's just part of the
dumbing down side because
you know they wanted you know the
internet used to be a place where you
could get all kinds of interesting
information and about it about
everything and they wanted it's becoming
so mediated that they just want it to be
this
ultra dumb down kind of consumer
experience where you go on youtube and
you'd see
just somebody you know you know putting
on makeup or talking about their cats or
something
they don't want it to be a vehicle for
people actually understand the world
they live in
yeah all these issues that we've talked
about getting your head chopped off on
social media
not having good access to information
through google getting a bunch of
propaganda misinformation etc
this is something that we've picked up
on in the liminal order and this is part
of the reason why we got together
is we have raised a info militia
that's what we call it an info militia
militias come up at a time at which
the government isn't providing for your
safety and security need to defend
yourself well in this case it's an
information war
and so we've come together hundreds of
men from all around the world come
together to form what we've called an
infant militia among other things
and we're dedicated to making sense of
the world and finding the right
information and becoming informed people
so that we can maintain our sovereignty
which is what this is about
access to information knowledge the
truth understanding of the world
that is about personal sovereignty and
that is what is at risk here
is our personal sovereignty and our
ability to be an individual
in the world and our ability to protect
ourselves and our families
and all that is at stake in this
election and so
i really appreciated uh all of this
conversation
here because it's also salient and it's
also on point
and it explains what we've seen over the
last few years
and we've now have also uh a map
of what's brought you know probably
clearly
going to happen moving forward we're
going to absent
a massive popular vote and electoral
landslide in either direction
right but even then who knows we're
going to see
you know accusations of electoral fraud
we're going to
uh see uh law fair strategies to
dispute the election we're going to see
perhaps uh the co-opting of the house
certification process
to keep trump out we're going to see
massive protests and mobilization
in the streets to raise the temperature
on everybody and to make everybody
scared and confused and distracted and
disoriented
and we're going to see all this working
together in concert
probably i mean obviously it's right now
but all the way through
uh election day you know september
october
starting tonight maybe with the 50 days
of siege that is supposed to happen in
washington dc which i'll be covering
all the way through the election clearly
not to be settled on election night
who knows how long it's going to stretch
into the future
i hope it doesn't get dragged out
for months or years or who knows what
but we really are
on the sort of the cusp of a new page of
history
where we're not exactly sure how it's
all going to go down
except we do know what the strategies
and tactics of the opposition are
and you have so clearly laid those out
for us there thank you so much
darren j beatty find him on twitter
guys you should definitely be following
him
here it is on the screen darren j beatty
you should also definitely be going to
revolver.news
president and everyone called it the new
drudge report
uh it is where i go every day to get
news and analysis from people
like darren who is an expert in his
field who
has been involved in ministration who
knows not only what's going on on the
ground
right now but understands how it all
fits into the grand and great
conversations
of humanity philosophy political theory
etc and thank you so much for coming on
and explaining what a
color revolution is and uh you know
let's do this again
in a few weeks or next month and touch
base and see where we are and keep
everybody up to date
so thank you very much darren i really
appreciate it and uh if you got any uh
parting words now's the time and uh you
know thank you
well thank you no parting words other
than thank you for having me on i hope
it was
uh it was educational
so certainly was follow darren darin jbd
uh on twitter follow me
jack murphy live uh at twitter go to the
website jackmurphylive.com get the book
democrat to deplorable it's on amazon
still selling like crazy i reached
number four
it was anti-racist white fragility
coddling of the american mind
and democrat to deplorable i'd like to
see the next push
knock white fragility out of that top
spot in anthropology i'd love that
check out the liminal order liminal
hyphen order dot com
and again revolver news darren jb thank
you so much talk to you soon buddy
thank you thank you bye-bye